<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Typescript on ( •–•) Mo Codes</title>
    <link>/blog/typescript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Typescript on ( •–•) Mo Codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020, Jane Doe.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/blog/typescript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using gRPC for Microservice Communication</title>
      <link>/using-grpc-for-microservice-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/using-grpc-for-microservice-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In traditional microservice architectures, communication between services is done via REST or sometimes for event driven communication, protocols like MQTT are employed. In a RESTful architecture, resources are identified by URIs (Uniform Resource Identifiers) and operations on those resources are performed using standard HTTP methods. Data Transfer Objects (DTOs) are represented as JSON or XML which are both lightweight and human readable formats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;gRPC on the other hand is a relatively newer framework which facilitates efficient communication using RPCs (Remote Procedure Calls) enabling services to call functions on other machines as if they were local. It is built on the use of a mechanism called Protobufs (Protocol Buffers) which supports strongly typed service contracts for DTOs and binary data encoding as opposed to JSON. Protobuf contracts are defined in .proto files which are used to generate code that can be used by a microservice akin to a library or SDK.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Prototypes and Classes in JavaScript (and TypeScript)</title>
      <link>/demystifying-prototypes-and-classes-in-javascript-and-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/demystifying-prototypes-and-classes-in-javascript-and-typescript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve worked within the JavaScript ecosystem, you’ve probably used an ES6 class data structure. But you may not know about its more primitive counterpart: prototypes. The core truth is that JavaScript is prototype-based language and one of the only mainstream object-oriented languages to use prototypal inheritance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Classes are just syntax sugar over prototypes and throwing TypeScript into the mix adds type safety but does not enforce runtime behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what are prototypes? A prototype is just another object that an object delegates to when a property or method is not found on itself and this allows for shared methods across multiple instances of an object. Every object gets a &lt;em&gt;[[Prototype]]&lt;/em&gt; slot automatically when it is created.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
